The Agecroft Collection
The Agecroft Collection
- Documents relating to Pendlebury, Pendleton, Prestwich etc, 1631-1787; 32 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/4
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Prestwich, co Lancs, 8 Dec 1683; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 232; GB/418/Agecroft/4/8
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to John Hopwood of Prestwich, chapman.
  - Lease of 3 acres of Common in Pendlebury, co Lancs, 5 Mar 1687; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 233; GB/418/Agecroft/4/9
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Robert Gartside of Pendlebury, blacksmith.
    5 Mar 1686/7
  - Lease of 3 acres of common with one road missing, 4 Feb 1688; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 234; GB/418/Agecroft/4/10
    4 Feb 1687/8
  - Lease of 12 acres of moor part of Swinton Moor, 8 Mar 1690; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 235; GB/418/Agecroft/4/11
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Thomas Godden of Pendlebury, gent.
    8 Mar 1689/90
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Whitlane within Pendleton, co Lancs, 27 Jun 1696; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 236; GB/418/Agecroft/4/12
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, gent, to Matthew Browne of Whitland, whitster.
    Term: 2 lives
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Pendleton, co Lancs, 2 Feb 1699; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 237; GB/418/Agecroft/4/13
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Thomas Holland of Pendleton, whitster.
    2 Feb 1698/9
  - Lease of closes in Agecroft, co Lancs, 20 Jun 1700; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 nos 238 & 239; GB/418/Agecroft/4/14
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Thomas Dauntesey of Manchester, gent, for his life.
  - Assignment of a lease of certain closes in Agecroft, co Lancs, 24 Jun 1700; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 nos 240 & 241; GB/418/Agecroft/4/15
    From Thomas Dauntesey of Manchester, gent, to Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, in consideration of an annuity of £18 during his life.
    Nos 240 & 241 are duplicates
  - Lease of six closes in Pendleton, co Lancs, 25 Jul 1700; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 242; GB/418/Agecroft/4/16
    From James Taylor of Gorton, gent, and others (trustees for Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq) to Robert Bradshaw of Newhall in Pendleton co Lancs, yeo.
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Pendleton, co Lancs, 19 Oct 1700; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 243; GB/418/Agecroft/4/17
    From James Taylor of Gorton, gent, and others (trustees for Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq) to Robert Holden the elder of Pendleton, whitster.
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Pendleton, co Lancs, 19 Oct 1700; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdle 1 no 244; GB/418/Agecroft/4/18
    From James Taylor of Gorton, gent, and others (trustees for Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq) to Thomas Holland of Pendleton, whitster.
  - Lease of a messuage etc in or near Whitlane within Pendleton, co Lancs, 28 Oct 1700; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 245; GB/418/Agecroft/4/19
    From James Taylor of Gorton, gent, and others (trustees for Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq) to Matthew Browne late of Whitlane within Pendleton and now of Elton co Lancs, whitster.
  - Lease of messuages etc in Pendleton, co Lancs, 30 Oct 1702; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 246; GB/418/Agecroft/4/20
    From James Taylor of Gorton, gent, and others (trustees for Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq) to Thomas Bradshaw of Manchester co Lancs, mercer.
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Prestwich, co Lancs, 7 Nov 1702; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 247; GB/418/Agecroft/4/21
    From James Taylor of Gorton, gent, and others (trustees for Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq) to John Hooperood [Hopwood] of Prestwich, husbandman.
  - Lease of closes in Pendlebury, co Lancs, 19 Mar 1705; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 248; GB/418/Agecroft/4/22
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Thomas Keighley of Pendlebury, husbandman.
    19 Mar 1704/5
  - Lease of two closes called Hilton Meadows in Pendleton, co Lancs, 30 Jun 1709; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 nos 249 & 250; GB/418/Agecroft/4/23
    From Christopher Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to William Marshall of Pendleton husbandman.
  - Lease of closes in Prestwich, co Lancs, 2 Feb 1720; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 251; GB/418/Agecroft/4/24
    From Edward Dauntesey of Pendlebury co Lancs, esq, to John Aslay of 'Loins' in the parish of Eccles co Lancs, husbandman.
    Term: 3 years
    2 Feb 1719/20
  - Lease of a messuage etc in or near Whitlane in Pendleton, co Lancs, 24 Mar 1720; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 252; GB/418/Agecroft/4/25
    From Edward Dauntesey of Agecroft co Lancs, esq, to Thomas Holland of Whitlane in Pendleton, whitster.
    24 Mar 1719/20
  - Lease of closes in Swinton, co Lancs, 22 Jun 1721; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 253; GB/418/Agecroft/4/26
    From Edward Dauntesey of 'Edgecroft' co Lancs, esq, John Wroe of Manchester, maltman, and Mary his wife (mother of the said Edward Dauntesey) to Robert Whittlawe of Manchester, innkeeper, for the term of his life.
  - Lease of two messuages etc in or near Whitlane in Pendleton, co Lancs, 4 Oct 1757; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 254; GB/418/Agecroft/4/27
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft co Lancs, esq, to Thomas Holland of Pendleton, gent.
  - Lease of a messuage etc in Pendlebury, co Lancs, 4 Dec 1780; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 255; GB/418/Agecroft/4/28
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, clerk, to William Thomason of Flixton co Lancs, farmer.
  - Lease of fields in Pendlebury for 14 years and Pendleton for 12 years, 2 Feb 1783; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 no 256; GB/418/Agecroft/4/29
    From Rev Mr Dauntesey to Nathaniel Chadwick. Assigned to Samuel Brierley for 19 years from 2 Feb 1784.
  - Lease of lands in the township of Pendlebury and parish of Eccles, 31 Jan 1787; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 bdl 2 nos 257 & 258; GB/418/Agecroft/4/30
    From Rev Mr Dauntesey to Jonathan Shaw.
    Term: 15 years from the 2 Feb 1787
  - Copy of the will of Alice Schofield of Prestwich, co Lancs, widow, 20 Jun 1676; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 264; GB/418/Agecroft/4/31
  - Copy of the will of Thomas Crompton of Prestwich Wood in the parish of Prestwich, co Lancs, gent, 18 Nov 1766; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 265; GB/418/Agecroft/4/32
    Proved 26 Jun 1776
- Documents relating to Agecroft Hall and land in Pendlebury, 1756-1821; 14 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 372-386; GB/418/Agecroft/5
  - Lease of Agecroft Hall etc, 12 Oct 1756; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 372; GB/418/Agecroft/5/1
    From Robert Billinge of the parish of Manchester, gent, on behalf of John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Peter Walker of Unsworth within Pilkington in the parish of Prestwich, and James Walker of Alkington, parish of Prestwich, husbandman.
  - Lease of Agecroft Hall etc, 24 Dec 1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 373; GB/418/Agecroft/5/2
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, esq, to Bridget Walker of Pilkington in the parish of Prestwich, widow, and others.
  - Lease of a farm, part of Agecroft Estate, 22 Nov 1780; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 374; GB/418/Agecroft/5/3
    From Rev Mr John Dauntesey of Agecroft, clerk, to Mr William Westbrook of Withington co Lancs.
  - Lease of a farm, part of Agecroft Estate, 4 Dec 1780; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 375; GB/418/Agecroft/5/4
    From Rev Mr John Dauntesey of Agecroft to Ralph Gregory of Rixton co Lancs.
  - Counterpart Lease of five closes of land in the Township of Pendlebury, 12 May 1784; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 376; GB/418/Agecroft/5/5
    From Rev John Dauntesey of Agecroft, clerk, to George Hankinson of Pendleton co Lancs, breadbaker.
    Term: 18 years from the 2 Feb 1784
  - Lease of a field etc in Pendlebury, co Lancs, 10 Oct 1787; Chetham's Library; GB/418/nos 377 & 378; GB/418/Agecroft/5/6
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, clerk, and William Thomason of Agecroft, farmer, to James Lever and Christopher Whalley, both of Manchester, calico printers, for 14 years.
  - Surrender of a lease of part of Agecroft Hall etc, 17 Oct 1789; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 379; GB/418/Agecroft/5/7
    From Ralph Gregory of Rixton co Lancs, farmer, to John Dauntesey of Agecroft in Pendlebury, clerk.
  - Lease of part of Agecroft Hall etc, 1791; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 380; GB/418/Agecroft/5/8
    From John Dauntesey of Agecroft, clerk, to John Catterall of Crowley co Ches, husbandman.
    Term: 7 years (Not executed)
  - Lease of lands in the Township of Pendlebury and Parish of Eccles, 9 May 1799; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 381; GB/418/Agecroft/5/9
    From Rev Mr John Dauntesey of Agecroft to Thomas Slater of Manchester, merchant.
    Term: 21 years from 2 Feb 1799
  - Lease of a plot or parcel of land or ground within Pendlebury, co Lancs, 25 Dec 1799; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 382; GB/418/Agecroft/5/10
    From Rev John Dauntesey of Agecroft to William Norton of Walness Lodge in Pendleton co Lancs, calico printer.
    Term: 21 years under the clear rent of £64 15s 0d payable on 24 Jun and 29 Sep
  - Agreement relative to removal of buildings etc on a plot of land in Pendlebury co Lancs, 11 Jun 1810; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 383; GB/418/Agecroft/5/11
    Between Rev John Dauntesey of Agecroft and Mr Michael Norton of Wallness Lodge in Pendleton co Lancs, calico printer.
  - Lease of a part of Agecroft Hall Estate, 7 Jul 1813; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 384; GB/418/Agecroft/5/12
    From John Hull, esq, of Chorley co Lancs to Elizabeth Catterall, widow, and her sons, William Catterall and John Catterall of Agecroft, farmers.
    Term: 7 years from Candlemas May 1814
    Rent: £360 payable 24 Jun yearly
  - Lease of a close of land in Pendlebury, 1 Sep 1813; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 385; GB/418/Agecroft/5/13
    From John Hull, esq, of Chorley co Lancs to Messrs John and James Taylor of Pendlebury, calico printers.
    Term: 7 years from 25 Dec 1813
    Rent: £50 payable 1 Jan yearly
  - Agreement to lease to William Thomason of Pendlebury, farmer, a messuage etc in Pendlebury for 5 years, 12 Dec 1821; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 3 no 386; GB/418/Agecroft/5/14
    Made by Richard Buck of Agecroft Hall in Pendlebury, clerk, and Elizabeth Hull of Chorley, spinster.
- Documents relating to Poulton, North Lancashire, 1622-1863; 68 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/6
  The Dauntesey family held land in Poulton in North Lancashire.
  - Lease [?of land in Poulton co Lancs], 16 Mar 1623; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 1; GB/418/Agecroft/6/1
    From John Rossall to Richard Rossall
    16 Mar 1622/3, 20 Jas I
  - Bond, 14 Mar 1623; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 2; GB/418/Agecroft/6/2
    From John to Richard Rossall
  - Lease [?of land in Poulton co Lancs], 9 Jan 1665; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 3; GB/418/Agecroft/6/3
    From John Singleton to R[ichard] Rossall
  - Lease [?of land in Poulton co Lancs], 2 Feb [1683]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 4; GB/418/Agecroft/6/4
    From James Wild to Rich[ard] Rossall
  - Bond, 3 Mar 1683; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 5; GB/418/Agecroft/6/5
    From James Wild to Tho[ma]s Singleton and Richard Rossall
    3 Mar 168[3/4]
  - Lease [?of land in Poulton co Lancs], 4 Nov 1684; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 6; GB/418/Agecroft/6/6
    From John Rossall to James Rossall
  - Assignment, 5 Jun 1690; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 7; GB/418/Agecroft/6/7
    From James Rossall to Laurence Hardman
  - Indenture, 22 Aug 1691; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 8; GB/418/Agecroft/6/8
    Between Rich[ard] Ashton, Thomas Winckley, Edmund Hornby, Chris Graddell, Chris Anderton and others.
  - Lease [?of land in Poulton co Lancs], 21 Mar [1692]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 9; GB/418/Agecroft/6/9
    From Rich Ashton, Thomas Winckley and others to Rich Rossall.
  - Conveyance of a cottage and lands etc in Carleton co Lancs, 22 Mar [1692]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 10; GB/418/Agecroft/6/10
    From Richard Ashton of Curedall co Lanc etc to Richard Rossall of Carleton, husbandman.
  - Will and codicil of Richard Hull, 31 Aug 1703; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 11; GB/418/Agecroft/6/11
  - Assignment, 2 Feb [1704]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 12; GB/418/Agecroft/6/12
    From Richard Rossall to Margery Hoole
  - Release, 29 April 1717; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 13; GB/418/Agecroft/6/13
    From Richard Dobson to Margery now the wife of Thomas Wild.
  - Release, 17 Oct 1720; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 14; GB/418/Agecroft/6/14
    From Jennet Dobson to Rich Hoole [?Hull].
  - Copy of the will of Thomas Brown, 8 Mar 1727; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 15; GB/418/Agecroft/6/15
  - Conveyance, 5 Nov 1728; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 16; GB/418/Agecroft/6/16
    From John Hull to R[ichard] Hull
  - Lease, 5 Feb 1731; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 17; GB/418/Agecroft/6/17
    From Thomas Hardman, Rich[ard] Dickson and John Singleton to Richard Hull.
    5 Feb 173[0/1]
  - Conveyance, 6 Feb [1730]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 18; GB/418/Agecroft/6/18
    From Thomas Hardman and John Singleton to Richard Hull.
  - Release, 7 June 1734; Chetham's Library; GB/418/nos 19 & 20; GB/418/Agecroft/6/19
    From Rob Nickson to John Hull and Rich Hull.
  - Copy of the will of John Hull, 28 Jun 1740; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 21; GB/418/Agecroft/6/20
  - Will of Richard Hull, 13 Apr 1745; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 22; GB/418/Agecroft/6/21
  - Will of Alice Buck, 5 Jan 1776; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 23; GB/418/Agecroft/6/22
  - Lease, 26 Feb 1779; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 24; GB/418/Agecroft/6/23
    From W[illia]m Gillibrand to Rich[ard] Hull
  - Priests Orders to Richard Buck, 20 Dec 1789; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 25; GB/418/Agecroft/6/24
  - Will of Ellen Breckel, 25 Apr 1794; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 26; GB/418/Agecroft/6/25
  - Probate of the will of Elizabeth Hull, 8 Jul 1802; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 27; GB/418/Agecroft/6/26
  - Appointment by King George III of the Rev Rich Buck, 17 Sep 1803; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1a no 28; GB/418/Agecroft/6/27
  - Assignment, 31 Dec 1803; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 29; GB/418/Agecroft/6/28
    From Jos[eph] Harrison to Thomas Birley
  - Feoffment, 14 Feb 1804; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 30; GB/418/Agecroft/6/29
    From [?] Hemer and others to Thomas Hull.
  - Demise, 31 Jan 1805; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 31; GB/418/Agecroft/6/30
    From James Hull to Rev Buck.
  - Mortgage, 14 Feb 1805; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 32; GB/418/Agecroft/6/31
    From Thomas Hull to Mrs Betty Adlington.
  - Letters Patent from George III to Rev R[ichard] Buck, 23 May 1806; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 33; GB/418/Agecroft/6/32
    Large broken seal
  - Consent of Rev Richard Buck, 26 May 1806; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 34; GB/418/Agecroft/6/33
  - Conformity of Rev Richard Buck, 26 May 1806; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 35; GB/418/Agecroft/6/34
  - Assignment, 2 Feb 1808; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 36; GB/418/Agecroft/6/35
    From Thomas Birley to Thomas Helme
  - Administration of Rich[ard] Hull to Marg Hull, 18 Feb 1809; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 37; GB/418/Agecroft/6/36
  - Settlement, 20 Feb 1809; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 38; GB/418/Agecroft/6/37
    From Mrs M Hull and others to Edmund Leigh.
  - Probate of the Will of Miss Margery Hull, 9 May 1809; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 39; GB/418/Agecroft/6/38
    Will dated 6 Jul 1802
  - Copy of the will of Ann Hull, 23 Aug 1809; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 40; GB/418/Agecroft/6/39
  - Memorandum of agreement, 22 Jan 1810; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 41; GB/418/Agecroft/6/40
    From Thomas Hull to Miss Ann Hull.
  - Assignment, 14 Feb 1811; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 42; GB/418/Agecroft/6/41
    From Mrs Betty Adlington to Thomas Hull.
  - Copy of the will of John Hull, 12 May 1813; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 43; GB/418/Agecroft/6/42
  - Probate of the will of John Hull, 3 Jan 1814; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 44; GB/418/Agecroft/6/43
  - Probate of the will of Ann Hull, 5 Mar 1817; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 45; GB/418/Agecroft/6/44
  - Probate of the will of Agnes Cooper, 9 Jul 1817; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 46; GB/418/Agecroft/6/45
  - Administration of Marg Hull, 2 Jun 1821; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 47; GB/418/Agecroft/6/46
  - Bond, 2 Feb 1822; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 48; GB/418/Agecroft/6/47
    From Thomas Helme to Miss Margaret Poslewite.
  - Probate of Will of Alice Cooper, 13 Apr 1826; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 49; GB/418/Agecroft/6/48
  - Assignment, 29 Jul 1826; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 50; GB/418/Agecroft/6/49
    From Thomas Helme to James Postlethwaite
  - Assignment, 25 Oct 1826; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 51; GB/418/Agecroft/6/50
    From James Postlewite and others to Rev Buck.
  - Lease, 12 Nov 1842; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 52; GB/418/Agecroft/6/51
    From Miss Hull to Captain Woodford
  - Release, 14 Mar 1846; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b no 53; GB/418/Agecroft/6/52
    From [?] Fazakerley to Miss Hull.
  - Various bills, receipts etc relating to the Hull family, nd [?19th century]; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 1b nos 54-56; GB/418/Agecroft/6/53
  - Conveyance [?concerning Cottam Hall Estate], 23 Nov 1758; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 4 no 77; GB/418/Agecroft/6/54
    From Joseph Hesketh to Thomas Cottam
  - [Lease and release] [?concerning Cottam Hall Estate], 6 & 7 Feb 1778; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 4 no 78; GB/418/Agecroft/6/55
    Between Thomas Cottam and Edward Jolly
  - Conveyance [?concerning Cottam Hall Estate], 13 Feb 1792; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 4 no 79; GB/418/Agecroft/6/56
    From James Jolly and others to Robert Broadbelt
  - Conveyance [?concerning Cottam Hall Estate], 13 Dec 1794; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 8 bdl 4 no 80; GB/418/Agecroft/6/57
    From Robert Broadbelt to Richard Buck
  - Abstract of the title of Gabriel Fielding esq, 1719-1802; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 162; GB/418/Agecroft/6/58
    To an estate called Staining Hall and several cottages and parcels of land in the township of Hardhorn with Newton in the county of Lancaster.
  - Abstract of title to Mr Fielding's premises purchased by Mr Swarbreck in Hardhorn with Newton co Lancs, 1791-1817; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 163; GB/418/Agecroft/6/59
  - Abstract of title to a close of land in Hardhorn called the Nook Meadow purchased by Mr Swarbreck, 1731-1817; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 164; GB/418/Agecroft/6/60
  - Abstract of the will and codicil of Thomas Whiteside late of Old Field Carr within the township of Hardhorn with Newton in the county of Lancaster, yeoman, decd, 1768-1771; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 165; GB/418/Agecroft/6/61
  - Abstract of the title of John Swarbreck esq, 1757-1811; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 166; GB/418/Agecroft/6/62
    To three messuages or dwelling houses and a close of land in Poulton co Lancs, and 4 acres of land in Hardhorn with Newton in the said county purchased by Robert Buck, esq, MD.
  - Abstract of the title of the trustees under the will of Edward Pedder the elder, decd, 1792-1863; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 167; GB/418/Agecroft/6/63
    To 2 closes of land in the township of Hardhorn with Newton in the co Lancs.
  - Additional Abstract of Mr John Swarbuck's title to a close of land called Andrews field sited in Poulton, 1786-1826; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 168; GB/418/Agecroft/6/64
  - Order from the quarter sessions to raise £60 for the repair of a bridge in the Forest of Rossendale in the Hundred of Blackburn, 15 Jan 1746; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 169; GB/418/Agecroft/6/65
  - Receipt for £12 for a pew in Poulton Parish Church, 1 Aug 1752; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 170; GB/418/Agecroft/6/66
    From John Airley, John Bird and Richard Tennant, all of Poulton, co Lancs, gents, to Alice Hull of Poulton.
  - Counterpart assignment of leasehold premises at Lambeth and of policies of insurance, 1 Apr 1790; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 171; GB/418/Agecroft/6/67
    From Stephen Lowdell to William Langley
  - Lease of premises in the Square, Preston, co Lancs, 1 Jun 1793; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 no 172; GB/418/Agecroft/6/68
    From Richard Hull to Will Barnes
    Term: 5 years
- Documents relating to Walton in le Dale and the Cooper Family, 1545-1769; 2 sub-series, 29 files; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Agecroft/7
  - Deeds relating to Walton in the Dale, 1545-1769; Chetham's Library; GB/418/81-100; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1
    - Feoffment, 23 Dec 1545; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 81; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/1
      By James Anderton to Thomas Alwertt
    - Bond, 25 Dec 1545; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 82; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/2
      From James Anderton to Thomas Alwert
    - Will of Thomas A[l]w[e]rte, 20 Nov 1573; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 83; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/3
      Proved 22 July 1574
    - Lease from Richard Hoghton to Edward Orte, 11 Apr 1606; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 84; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/4
      4 Jas I
    - Will of Alice Orte, 2 Sep 1620; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 85; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/5
      Proved 7 Nov 1620
    - Fine between George Sutch and Thomas Nelson, 21 Aug 1637; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 86; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/6
      13 Chas I
    - Fine between George Sutch and Thomas Nelson, 21 Aug 1637; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 87; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/7
      13 Chas
    - Articles of agreement between Robert Billinge and Katherine daughter of Richard Boulton, 10 Nov 1708; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 88; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/8
    - Bond from William Almond to John Billinge and others, 26 Aug 1715; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 89; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/9
    - Probate of will of Lawrence Pemberton, 17 May 1720; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 90; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/10
      Will dated 30 Mar 1720
      Paper and parchment
    - Assignment by William Gerard to Robert Hankinson and others, 14 May 1724; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 91; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/11
    - Copy of will of John Billinge, 25 Aug 1724; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 92; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/12
    - Will of Alice Billinge, 2 Dec 1724; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 93; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/13
    - Probate of the will of Thomas Critchley, 16 May 1732; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 94; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/14
      Will dated 26 Dec 1728
    - Release, 18 Sep 1732; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 95; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/15
      From Alice Almond and others to executors of will of John Billinge.
    - Probate of will of Ellen Crouchley, 18 Oct 1746; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 96; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/16
      Will dated 16 Aug 1746
    - Administration of goods of Thomas Aldcroft granted to Mathew Aldcroft, 12 Jul 1759; Chetham's Library; GB/418/Box 9 bdl 5 no 97; GB/418/Agecroft/7/1/17